E-mail: gregor.panic@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregorpanic/

Web: https://glhfgreg.github.io/

GREGOR PANIČ

GAME DESIGNER

PROFILE

Experienced game designer with a broad skill set and experience – from gameplay systems, player controllers, levels, to game AI. I turn high-level concepts into practical designs that can be prototyped and evaluated. I have a track record leading teams with an iterative and agile development process, focusing on quick prototyping and playtesting at its core. Additionally, I'm very comfortable being hands-on – implementing designs in various engines and tools.

EXPERIENCE

Embark Studios, Malmö, Sweden - Technical Designer, Track Owner

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

- Worked on wim, a social, multiplayer, creative sandbox.
- Lead an interdisciplinary team with a focus on NPCs and game AI.
- Worked closely with the creative lead to define the vision for NPCs, setting high-level goals, scope and roadmap from prototype to final deliverable.
- Provided design feedback to make NPCs meaningful and ensure cohesion.
- Lead the effort to create and maintain up-to-date documentation for NPCs.
- Point of contact for NPCs in charge of communication with other teams to help manage key stakeholders.
- Lead brainstorming and playtest sessions and mentored junior designers.
- Co-designed a systemic, living world with emergent events.
- Designed multiple NPC archetypes and developed workflows to build them.
- Designed and developed multiple creative player tools for manipulating the world.
- Designed a dynamic difficulty system that creates challenges for players.
- Co-designed the main social hub for 30 players and 30 NPCs.
- Implemented several NPC behaviors using Rust within a custom engine.
- Worked on <u>The Finals</u>. Enhanced world interactivity by designing various smart objects and interactions.

Frictional Games, Malmö, Sweden — Gameplay programmer & designer

SEPTEMBER 2016 - JUNE 2022

- Worked on Amnesia: Rebirth, an atmospheric first-person horror game.
- Pushed multiple levels from concept to shippable quality. This included coordinating art, tech and sound to achieve the desired vision.
- Designed and implemented 6 main levels and 2 main enemies (the Ghoul and the Wraith).
- Designed the fear system the central mechanic of the game.

- Developed an AI director for the Wraith including a position selection algorithm and a system for maintaining tension.
- Integrated Tobii eye tracking for <u>SOMA</u> and developed eye tracking features for the player controller.
- Designed levels and multiple player gadgets for an unannounced project.
- Programming was done in AngelScript and C++ in a custom engine.

Self-employed, Maribor, Slovenia — Game developer

SEPTEMBER 2013 - SEPTEMBER 2016

- Made Welkin Road, a first-person parkour game with grappling hooks.
- Solo project where I did art, game design, level design and programming.
- Designed over 20 levels and collected playtest data to fine tune difficulty and progression.
- Developed a custom player controller with parkour mechanics such as wall running and jumping, grapple hooks, sliding, vaulting and climbing.
- Made in Unity using C#.

TOOLS

C#, AngelScript, C++, Miro, Git, SVN, Unreal Blueprints, Unity, Godot, Blender, HPL Engine, Rust, JIRA, Trello, GitHub.

EDUCATION

University of Maribor, Slovenia — MS in Computer Science 2012 - 2015, Maribor, Slovenia

University of Maribor, Slovenia — BS in Computer Science 2009 - 2012, Maribor, Slovenia

SMALLER PROJECTS

OMG it's Mr.MANO!, Godot - 2024

https://davidpdrsn.itch.io/mano

Experimental game where you resize your hand to give the best high fives. Entry for GMTK 2024 game jam. Worked on design and programming as part of a team.

Stagehand, Unreal Engine - 2024

https://glhfgreg.itch.io/stagehand

You play the lead role in an 80s sit-com, trying to use slapstick humor to make the audience laugh. Entry for Global Game Jam 2024. Worked on design and programming as part of a team.

Almighty Dice, Unreal Engine - 2022

https://measuring.itch.io/almighty-dice

A 1v1 competitive dice throwing game. Entry for GMTK 2022. Worked on design and programming as part of a duo.